菲比，来
Here you go,Pheebs.
谁要吃我的特制巧克力方饼？
Who wants one of my special home-baked brownies?
我要一块
I'll have one.
算了 不要了
-That's okay. -I'm not having one.
不是，是我牙痛
No,no. It's just my tooth.
好 我要一块
-All right. -I'll have one.
你要找牙医吗？ 我认识一个好医生
So you need a dentist? I've got a good one.
谢了，我也认识一个 只是我不能见他（亦同“见不到他”）
Thanks. I have a good one too. I just can't see him.
这就是隐形牙医的问题
See,that is the problem with invisible dentists.
一看见那些到处乱飞的金属工具就害怕
lt's very unsettling to see all those metal tools just flying around.
你为什么不能去找他？
Why can't you go to him?
因为我每次去看牙医 就会有人死
Because every time I go to the dentist,somebody dies.
真诡异，我每次去看牙医
That's so weird. Every time I go to the dentist...
都会偷看医生的紧身上衣
... I look down the hygienist's blouse.
…什么？
What?
第一次是玛丽阿姨
First it was my Aunt Mary.
然后是我的邮差约翰
And then there was John,my mailman.
然后是我的牛仔朋友 艾拜诺巴伯
And then my cowboy friend,Albino Bob.
这些人真的都死了？
And all these people actually died?
对，当我坐在诊疗椅上时
Yes. While I was in the chair.
所以我都自己保健牙齿 不是为了口腔卫生
That's why I take care of my teeth. It's not about oral hygiene.
我用牙线是为了救人
I floss to save lives.
拜托，你没有杀人
Come on,you didn't kill anybody.
只是这些人死的时候 你刚好去看牙医
These people just happened to die when you went to the dentist.
这只是巧合
It's just a coincidence.
你去告诉他们 啊，不行，他们死了
Tell that to them. Oh,you can't! They're dead!
本集播出：“巨大的戳人工具”
The One With the Giant Poking Device
“中央公园”
甘瑟，谢了
Thanks,Gunther.
可以给一张纸巾吗？
Can I get a napkin too?
你还不够称心如意吗？
Oh,like you don't already have everything.
你痛得很厉害，去看牙医吧
You're in pain. Would you just go to the dentist? Just go.
好，但如果你是下一名受害者
Fine. But if you're my next victim...
别化身成厉鬼跑回来 把我吸进电视里
...don't come back as a poltergeist who sucks me into the TV set.
保证不会
I promise.
但还是欢迎你来找我
Although,don't feel like you can't visit.
钱德在吗？
Hey,is Chandler here?
不在
No. No,he's not.
乔伊看到珍妮丝亲她的前夫
You guys,Joey just saw Janice kissing her ex-husband.
什么？
What?
你要怎么办？ 要怎么告诉钱德？
What are you gonna do? How are you gonna tell Chandler?
我一直在想这件事 最好的办法就是…
I was thinking about that. I think the best way would be...
不要说
...to not.
乔伊，既然你知道了 就得告诉他
Joey,if you know about this,you have to tell him.
那他就完了，等于是杀了他
It'll kill him. It'll just kill him.
等我去看牙医吧 或许我会杀了他
Wait till I go to the dentist. Maybe I'll kill him.
丑裸男在睡吊床 好像彩色塑泥肥肉工厂喔
I think Naked Guy's using a hammock. It's like a Play-Doh fat factory.
我要去看牙医了，听我说
I'm going to the dentist. So listen...
小心会让你们掉进去的东西
...just be on the lookout for anything that you could fall into...
或是会掉下来的东西
...or that can fall on you...
或是…
...or....
总之要小心
All right,just look out!
我还想要…
And I also just want to....
我只想告诉你们…
I just want to tell you all that....
我有一个麻烦 我得去忙上几个小时
I have a problem. I have to go into work for a few hours.
有一些小孩大闹智人展览
Some kids messed up the Homo sapien display.
怎么个闹法？
What did they do?
他们涂掉了“人”（剩下的Homo意为同性恋）
They painted over the word "sapien," for one thing.
然后又把人偶重新排列 这个就不说了
Then they rearranged the figures. Let's just leave it at that.
要我帮你照顾班吗？
Do you want me to watch Ben for you?
我正要拜托你，谢谢
That's what I was gonna ask. Thank you.
等一下，让我来如何？
Wait,hello! What about me?
你！你想照顾班？
You. You want to watch Ben?
太好了 不过我拜托莫妮卡是因为…
That would be great! I just asked Monica...
她的生活很空虚
... because I know how empty her life is.
我有个科学问题
I got a science question.
如果智人真的是“同性恋者”
If the Homo sapiens were,in fact,"homo" sapiens...
所以才会绝种吗？
...is that why they're extinct?
乔伊，智人就是人（意同“同性恋也是人”）
Joey,Homo sapiens are people.
我没有歧视的意思
Hey,I'm not judging.
小班，你看，汤匙
Look,Benny! Spoon!
汤匙
Spoon!
我看他觉得很无聊
Come on. All right,you know what? I think he's bored.
来，要不要玩坐飞机？
Here. You wanna play the airplane game?
要不要玩给瑞秋看？过来
You wanna show Rachel? Come here.
你想玩好玩的？好
You wanna do something fun? Okay.
你最勇敢了，最最勇敢了
You're so brave. You're so brave! Yes,you are.
没事了
-You're so brave. -You're okay.
他没事，把他放下
He's fine. Let's just put him down.
宝贝，过来，你好乖
Come here,babe. Yes,you're such a good boy.
你怎么可以撞到他？ 罗斯很信任我，他会怎么说？
How could you do that to him?! Ross trusted me! What's he gonna say?
不会的，我们不会告诉他
Nothing,because we're not telling him.
不会吗？ 不会
-We're not? -No.
哦，我喜欢这样
All right,I like that.
你没事，你没事对吧？
So we're okay. We're okay,aren't we?
不，你有事，这里肿起来了
No,we're not okay. There's a bump.
什么肿起来？
What bump?
天哪，把它压下去！
Oh,my God! Well,push it in! Push it in!
我不能把它压下去
I cannot push it in!
好，我们得分散注意力 好
Okay,we're gonna need a distraction.
就是这样 好
That's it.
我知道了 好
I got it!
罗斯一走进来
The second Ross walks in...
你就拉他进房间 使出浑身解数
...take him to your bedroom and do whatever you do...
让他快活
...that makes him go "rheeeee!"
或者…
Or...
我们也可以帮他戴帽子
...we could put a hat on his head.
帽子！没错，我们需要帽子 要去哪里找小帽子？
A hat! Yes! We need a hat! Where are we gonna find a tiny little hat?
我去拿雨天小熊
I'll get Rainy Day Bear!
因为他有办法？
Because he'll know what to do?
天哪，你真是天才
Oh,my God. You're a genius!
好像缝死了
It's kind of sewn on.
拿来… 好
Give it. Give it.
今天这里真是血腥啊
It's just like a bloodbath in here today!
等一下…
Hey,hold on a second. Hold on a second.
你觉得这串珍珠漂亮吗？
Do you think these pearls are nice?
我比较喜欢登山车
I'd prefer a mountain bike.
珍妮丝的生日快到了 我想送她特别的礼物
Janice's birthday's coming. I wanna get her something special.
陪我进去 慢着
-Come in here with me. -Wait!
你想来点特别的？送花嘛
You wanna get her something special? Get her flowers.
送糖，送口香糖 女生都喜欢口香糖
Get her candy. Get her gum. Girls love gum.
好主意“亲爱的珍妮丝 祝你哈巴波巴（泡泡糖品牌）生日快乐”
That's a good idea. "Dear Janice: Have a Hubba-Bubba birthday."
我想送一份严肃的礼物
I'd like to get her something serious.
你要严肃的东西
You want something serious.
知道吗？你应该送…
You know what you should do? You should get her one of those...
灌肠剂
... barium enemas.
那个严肃得要命
Those are dead serious.
这样她以后就不用自己买了
And you know she'll never get one for herself.
我要进去 你以后不要送东西给我
Look,I'm gonna go in here. And you don't buy me anything,ever!
不行！你不能送她珍珠项链
You can't! You can't. You can't buy her pearls.
不行，不行，不行…
You just can't,you can't,you can't!
为什么不行？
Why not?
天哪
Oh,God.
是这样的
Here's the thing.
是这样的…
This is the thing. Okay,the thing is
是怎样？ 好
What is the thing?
我那天去床垫大王的卖场
I went down to the Mattress King's showroom...
看到珍妮丝在亲她的前夫
...and I saw Janice kissing her ex-husband.
什么？
What?
他们在他的办公室里
They were in his office.
她不会亲他的，她跟我在一起
She wouldn't do that. She's with me.
是真的，我亲眼看到
I'm telling you,I saw it.
你看错了，你错了
Well,you're wrong. You're wrong.
我没有看错
I'm not wrong.
我巴不得我看错了
I wish I was.
对不起
I'm sorry.
现在觉得送灌肠剂不错吧？
Bet that barium enema doesn't sound so bad now.
穿整套比较不奇怪 也免得帽子太显眼
It makes more sense as an ensemble. And it takes the focus off the hat.
你们还活着！
Oh! You're alive! You're alive!
我不是保证过没有人会死？
I promised you no one would die,didn't l?
待会就知道了 借我打电话给我认识的人
We'll see about that. Can I use your phone to call everyone I know?
你用吧，我们没钱，请便
Sure. We have no money. Go ahead.
喂，你没死！ 好，再见
Hey,you're not dead! Okay,see you.
莫妮卡
Monica.
天哪，他叫我的名字
Oh,my God! He just said my name!
你听到了吗？
Did you hear that?
莫妮卡，砰
Monica bang!
我听到了
Okay,I heard that.
他是不是说“莫妮卡，砰”？
Did he just say,"Monica bang"?
天哪，他要告我的密
Oh,my God! He's gonna rat me out!
莫妮卡，砰
Monica bang!
小乖乖，你不能再说了
Sweetie,you need to stop saying that now.
没什么大不了的 根本不值得一提
It's no big deal. It's not even worth mentioning.
懂吗？我们经常撞来撞去
You see? We all do it all the time.
懂吗？看我的
See? Watch this.
莫妮卡，砰，大家，砰
Monica bang! Everybody bang!
班，砰
Ben bang!
瑞秋，砰
Rachel bang!
砰，瑞秋，砰
Bang,Rachel! Bang!
很好玩吧？ 你看
-Oh,isn't it fun? -Look at that!
大家都在砰
We all do it!
我不撞了 你还好吗？
-Okay,I'm stopping now. -Are you okay?
如果不是床头板，根本不值得
You know,if it's not a headboard,it's just not worth it.
我的小宾宾好吗？
How's my Bing-a-ling?
我不知道
I don't know.
你说呢？
You tell me.
你有话要对我说吗？
Anything you want to tell me?
因为要是你…你应该…
Because if you.... You should
你会告诉我
You would tell me.
你为什么瞪着眼睛？
Why are your eyes so wide?
你说呢？
You tell me.
也许是因为 我和旧情人搞在一起
Maybe it's because I was just fooling around with my ex.
不不不，不不不，那是你！
Oh,no. That was you!
我的天
Oh,my God!
很好 你怎么知道？
-All right! -How did you know?
乔伊说的，他看到你们接吻
Joey told me. He saw you two kissing.
在公园里？
In the park?
不是，在他的办公室 你们亲了几次？
No. In his office. How many kisses were there?
就那两次
Just those two!
为什么？…
Why?
为什么接吻？你们不该接吻的
Why was there kissing? There should be no kissing!
对不起，我非常非常…
Oh,I'm sorry,honey. I'm so,so....
我非常…抱歉，我只是…
I'm so,so sorry. I just....
其实是…我喘不过气来
What happened was l.... I can't breathe.
可以给我一个袋子吗？
Can you get me a bag or something?
拿去（提高二氧化碳浓度，缓解心跳和呼吸过快）
Here. Here.
是收据
It's the receipt.
给我
I'll take it.
听着，我一定要知道
Look,I've got to know.
你跟我结束了吗？
Are you finished with me?
你跟他结束了吗？
Are you finished with him?
你还爱他？
Do you still love him?
你还爱我？
Do you still love me?
好，听我说
All right,look...
我需要明确的答案，好吗？
...I'm gonna need an actual answer here,okay?
你选哪一个？
So which is it?
他还是我？
Him or me?
我不知道
I don't know.
要是你还活着，请接电话
Okay,if you're alive,you answer your phone!
班，我不会告诉爸爸 你在晚餐前吃冰激凌
Okay,Ben,I won't tell your daddy that you had ice cream before dinner...
你也不能说出那个小小的意外
...if you won't tell him about our little bonking incident.
第一，班应该不懂什么是贿赂
Number one,I don't think Ben understands the concept of bribery.
第二，我…
And number two,I
怎么了？
What?
你说“第二”
You said "number two."
我也说了第一
I also said "number one."
我知道
I know.
大家好
Hey,everyone!
我的乖儿子好不好？
How's my little boy?
他好得很 对不对，班？
He's perfect. Aren't you,Ben?
他好得不得了 你们带他去捕鲸吗？
-He's never been better. -What did you do,take him whaling?
莫妮卡
Monica.
天哪，他说了你的名字 太棒了，干得好
Oh,my God! He just said your name! That's great! Good job,Ben!
莫妮卡，砰
Monica bang!
没错
That's right.
那就是我爆炸的声音
That's what I'd sound like if I exploded.
诅咒解除了 我联络了所有认识的人
The curse is broken! I called everybody I know...
大家都活着
...and everyone is alive!
丑裸男一动也不动
Ugly Naked Guy looks awfully still.
天哪，我又杀了一个人
My God,I killed another one!
诅咒变强了 那么胖的人也害得死
The curse is getting stronger too,to bring down something that big.
也许他只是在睡觉
Maybe he's just taking a nap.
我告诉你 他从早上开始就没动过
I'm telling you,he hasn't moved since this morning.
我们应该求援
We should call somebody.
说我们在偷窥的裸男不动了？
Tell them the naked guy we stare at isn't moving?
我们得弄清楚他的死活
We've got to find out if he's alive.
怎么弄清楚？根本没办法
How are we gonna do that? There's no way.
有一个办法
Well,there is one way.
他的窗子开着，我建议…
His window's open. I say...
我们戳他
...we poke him.
我们每次吃中国菜都会留筷子
You know how we save all those chopsticks...
又不知道为什么
...for no reason when we get Chinese food?
现在有用了
Well,now we got a reason.
怎么用？
What?
我们要做一个很长的探测器
We're fashioning a very long poking device.
好
All right.
你怎么了？
Hey,what's the matter?
我跟珍妮丝谈过了
I talked to Janice.
天哪，她要回到他身边吗？
Oh,my God. Is she going back to him?
她不知道
She doesn't know.
她说她两个都爱
Says she loves us both.
早上醒来时，我在恋爱
I woke up this morning,I was in love.
我原本很快乐
I was happy!
那十二包保险套本来买得也值得
It serves me right for buying that 12-pack of condoms.
现在连退都不能退 因为收据被她咬烂了
And now I can't even return them,because she choked on the receipt!
你要怎么办？
What are you gonna do?
不知道
I don't know.
你会怎么办？
You know? What would you do?
我的做法不重要
It doesn't matter what I'd do.
别这样…说嘛
Come on. Come on. Tell me.
好吧…
All right...
这种话你八成不爱听，但是…
...you probably won't want to hear this...
如果是我…这纯属个人意见
... but if it was me,and this is just me...
我会退出
... I'd bow out.
什么？
What?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
他们有一个孩子
They have a kid together...
你懂吗？
...you know?
他们是一家人
They're,like,a family.
要是…我不晓得
And if,I don't know...
要是他们有机会破镜重圆
...if there's a chance they can make that work...
我不会想当那个障碍
... I wouldn't want to be the guy who stood in the way.
你还好吧？
You okay?
要不要来戳裸男？
You wanna come poke a nude guy?
他终于睡着了
Well,he's finally asleep.
他头上那个肿包…
About that bump on his head....
你确定那是新的？
Are you sure it's a new bump?
我没有恶意 但我一直觉得他满头是包
No offense,but I've always thought of Ben as a fairly bumpy-headed child.
撞到头也没关系 小孩子经常撞到头
It's okay if he bumps his head. Kids bump their heads all the time.
你第一次照顾他 已经尽力了
It was your first time babysitting. You did your best.
我有尽力
I did!
我知道
I know.
不过你得随时盯着
You just have to watch them all the time.
我有，我盯得很紧
I did! I watched! I watched!
我眼睁睁看着莫妮卡 撞到他的头
I watched Monica bang his head against that thing!
是莫妮卡撞的？
Monica did it?
莫妮卡，你有没有发现 班今天怪怪的？
Did you notice anything weird about Ben today?
没有，怎么了？
No,why?
我刚才在陪他玩 我们唱了“字母歌”
I was just playing with him,and we were doing the "Alphabet Song"...
他一向很会唱 今天却漏了E和F
...which he's good at. But he left out "E" and "F."
仿佛那两个字母从他脑子里掉出来了
It's like they just,I don't know,fell out of his head.
真的？
Really?
还有，他走起路来
Oh,and also,he's walking...
不太对劲
... kind of funny.
似乎左脚动得比右脚快
It's like his left leg is moving a lot faster than his right leg.
他一直在里面…
Yeah,he's in there,just....
天哪，我害了你的儿子
Oh,my God! I wrecked your baby!
希望你下了地狱 还会觉得好玩
I hope it's still funny when you're in hell.
混蛋
You jerk!
你明知我有多爱他！ 莫妮卡，砰，莫妮卡，砰
-You know how much I love that kid! -Monica bang! Monica bang!
我去拿帽子
I'll get the hat.
我有一件事要告诉你
I have something to tell you.
请你让我说完
And I want you to let me get through it...
因为…
... because...
要说出口并不容易
...it's not gonna be easy.
我觉得你应该回到盖瑞身边
I think you should go back with Gary.
我不想当拆散家庭的人
I don't want to be the guy that breaks up a family.
我的父母分手 都是那个男人害的
You know,when my parents split up,it was because of that guy.
每次见到他，我都会想
Whenever I'd see him,I'd always think...
“是你害他们不能在一起的”
... "You're the reason. You are why they're not together."
我恨那个人
And I hated that guy.
不管他人有多好 还给我爸带来幸福
And it didn't matter how nice he was or how happy he made my dad.
这么做是正确的
It's the right thing to do.
你说得对
You're right.
天哪，在我说再见之前
Oh,God. But before I can say goodbye...
有件事我一定要你知道
...there's something I really need you to know.
我对你的感觉…
The way I feel about you...
让我终于了解
...it's like I finally understand...
莱昂纳尔里奇（黑人摇滚歌星）歌中的含意
...what Lionel Ritchie's been singing about.
我们的一切
You know? I mean,what we have...
就像演电影一样
...it's like movie love.
你是我的精神伴侣
You're my soul mate.
我们居然无法厮守到老
I can't believe we're not gonna spend the rest of our lives together.
那就不要离开我
Then don't leave me.
什么？
What?
忘了我说的话 我是随便说说，选我吧
Forget what I said! I was babbling! Pick me!
不，你说得对 我应该再给婚姻一次机会
No,you were right! I gotta give my marriage another chance.
不，你不能
No,you don't!
不，你应该再给离婚一次机会
I say you have to give your divorce another chance!
亲爱的，你不必委屈于我心中一半儿的位置
Sweetie, you should not have to settle for just half my heart.
我要委屈于你心中的一半儿位置，或者四分之一
l'll settle for half your heart.l'll settle for a quarter.
一点儿，细微，一个心房也可以
l'll settle for a little, tiny--A ventricle.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不要走
Don't go.
不，我该走了
No,I gotta go.
亲爱的…
Honey. Honey.
大家都在看 我不在乎
-People are looking. -I don't care.
我不在乎
I don't care!
好了
Yeah,okay.
我要走了
I'm leaving now.
你走不了，我拿了你的鞋子
You can't leave! I have your shoe!
再见，钱德宾
Goodbye,Chandler Bing.
瑞秋有一双紫红色的
Rachel has those in burgundy.
记住，这么大 又长的东西很难操作
Remember,something this big and long will be very difficult to maneuver.
幸好我有这方面的经验
Fortunately,I have experience in that area.
今天你怎么回事？12点钟吗？（勃起）
What are you, 1 2 today?
专心一点好吗？ 一个裸男的性命岌岌可危
Can we please focus here? A naked man's life hangs in the balance.
他一定已经死了
I'm telling you,he's dead.
我们会戳到一个死胖子
What we're about to have here is a dead fat guy on a stick!
各位先生、女士，戳吧
All right,ladies and gentlemen,let's poke.
稳着点
Steady.
慢慢来
再高一点
Okay,a little higher.
注意角度
Careful of the angle.
好…靠近窗户了
Okay,okay. We're approaching the window.
把探针伸进去
Thread the needle. Thread the needle.
他还活着…
He's alive! He's alive!
而我们还在戳他
And yet we're still poking him.
收回探测器、收回探测器
Okay,retract the device! Retract the device!
他好像不太爽
He does not look happy.
轮到他亮出他的“探针”了
Now he's showing us his poking device.
兄弟，你绝对伸不过来的
Hey,that's never gonna make it all the way over here,buddy!
我会紧紧拥你在怀里（莱昂纳尔里奇）
I'll hold you close in my arms
我无法抵挡你的魅力
I can't resist your charms
爱人啊
And love
爱人
Love
我愿为你做尽傻事
I'll be a fool for you
无庸置疑
I'm sure
你知道我并不介意
You know I don't mind
我并不介意
Oh,you know I don't mind
是的
Yes
你就是我的全世界
You mean the world to me
我知道
Oh,I know I know
在你身上
I've found I've found
我已找到
In you
无尽的爱
My endless love